picturepeople.com 2008-09-16

# The Picture People -Privacy

The Picture People Privacy Pledge 

We might be all about fun when it comes to taking portraits, but your privacy and security is something we take very seriously. This page contains our policy on how we collect and use personal information, and how we work to maintain the security of that information. Our privacy policy is regularly reviewed to make sure we continue to serve the privacy interests of our customers. We reserve the right to change and update the privacy policy and these changes will be posted on our web site. We encourage you to visit this page from time to time to ensure you are aware of any changes we may have made. 

Personal Information and Security

We collect personally identifiable information about you that you specifically provide to us. This includes, for example, the data you provide when you request further information, sign up for a service, respond to a survey or enter a contest or a sweepstakes online or when you visit a studio.  
We use this information: 

> • To provide you with the products, services or benefits you request   
>  • To develop and improve our products and services   
>  • To improve the content of our site and its usefulness to you   
>  • For marketing and promotional purposes 

We may contact you by mail, e-mail or telephone to inform you about products and services, including special promotions and coupons, which we think may be of interest to you.   
If you do not want to be contacted by **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** for promotional purposes, you may indicate your preference by mailing a written request to: Attention: Marketing Unsubscribe, 1800 10th Street, Suite 300 Plano, TX  75074\. Please indicate which name, address, phone number & email address you would like to have removed from our mailing list.

We may, from time to time, share this information with other reputable organizations whose products or services we think you might find interesting and those that match your possible needs. We employ measures to protect against the unauthorized disclosure of your personal information to third parties. We require that any organization with which we share information also take measures to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of personal information.  
If you do not want **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** to share your information please send an e-mail to: [donotshare@picturepeople.com](mailto:donotshare@picturepeople.com) or you may call Customer Service at 1-877-YOU-GRIN or mailing a written request to: Attention: Marketing Sharing, 1800 10th Street, Suite 300 Plano, TX  75074\. Please indicate which name, address, phone number & email address we should not share.

What information does **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** collect?

Information that you provide to us

We collect information you provide when you visit our physical studios, register with us, open an account, place an order, upload photos, invite others to view your photos, send us an e-mail or call us, enter a sweepstakes or enroll in a club or service. This information may include the following:

> • Your name  
>  • Your mailing address  
>  • Your e-mail address  
>  • Your phone number  
>  • The names and birthdates of your children  
>  • Applicable **Picture People** membership program numbers

It may also include information you submit about other people; for example, the name and address (e-mail and postal) of other people you invite to the site, or ask us to send products or gift cards to. We also collect information you submit for the personalization of products, such as calendars or mugs. 

Information collected through web technologies

We may track and collect your IP address, type of web browser you are using, your domain server, the type of computer you use and and use "cookies."

IP address

We do log IP addresses and we use them to monitor things such as the number of visitors to our web site. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you are using your browser on the Internet. Like most web sites, the servers that serve our web site automatically identify your computer by its IP address. 

Cookies

We may utilize "cookies." A cookie is a file that can be placed on your computer’s hard drive by our web site. It may contain coded information that allows us to remember who you are and how you use our site. For example, a cookie may remind us that you are a registered user and tell us that you do not need to log in every time. We try to ensure that cookies do not contain personal information that may be identified by a third party reading the contents of a cookie. We can only use the i nformation in a cookie to identify you after the information in the cookie is combined with information kept by us. We use this information to develop a better site for our customers, and reserve the right to disclose it to third parties on an aggregate basis. Site usage patterns for individual customers are protected from disclosure. If you choose to set your browser to reject cookies, we will not be able to make auto-login functionality available to you, including giving you access to your address book without first entering your **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** user name and password.

Other information 

We use technology that allows us to identify what type of browser you are using, the web site from which you enter **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** and the pages you view as you tour our site. This technology helps us compile aggregate statistics about our online guests and their use of **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** , which allows us to make improvements in design and content to better serve you. This technology does not identify you personally - it simply helps us compile statistics about our visitors and how they use our site.

How does **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** use the information it collects?

We use this information to provide services to you on our web site and in our retail studios. We may notify you by postal mail or e-mail about our products or services or promotional offers.

Who does **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** share information with?  
  
We will share personal customer information with our agents, representatives and trusted service providers and contractors for limited purposes, including fulfilling customer orders; offering certain products and services in connection with our web site; communicating with customers; providing customer service; enhancing and improving customers’ shopping experiences; enabling access to our partners’ sites; and completing credit card transactions. We also may, from time to time, share this information with other reputable organizations whose products or services we think you might find interesting and those that match your possible ne eds.  
**THE PICTURE PEOPLE** reserves the right to cooperate with law enforcement officials in the investigation of alleged unlawful activities of our customers related to electronic communication transmitted on our site. **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** will have no legal liability for such disclosures. We may also provide information to other organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction for use only in connection with this purpose.

How do I access and make changes to my preferences to receive e-mail?

When you establish a **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** account, your account automatically indicates that you want to receive promotional information from **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** regarding news about **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** products, services and events, as well as special offers and promotions for **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** or our business partners. If you do not want to be contacted by **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** for promotional purposes, you may indicate your preference by calling Customer Service at 1-877-YOU-GRIN, contacting your local studio, sending an email to[ customerservice@picturepeople.com](mailto:customerservice@picturepeople.com), or mailing a written request to: Attention: Email Unsubscribe, 1800 10th Street, Suite 300 Plano, TX  75074\. If receiving promotions via email, you may also [click here to unsubscribe.](mailto:picturepeople@prq0.com?subject=unsubscribe) Note: It may take up to 10 days for your name to be removed from our list. You must unsubscribe using the same email address the message was sent to. We also adhere to the CAN-SPAM laws required by the FTC.

How do I access and make changes to my personal information?  
  
You can modify your personal information by going to [www.picturepeople.com](http://www.picturepeople.com/), then go to SmileStore and follow the account management prompts. If you wish to delete your personal information simply call Customer Service at 1-877-YOU-GRIN and a Customer Service representative will be glad to assist you.

How does **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** handle contest and survey responses?

Periodically, **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** will invite customers to participate in contests and surveys. The information we collect from these contests and surveys may be associated with individual customer accounts and used by **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** to improve your overall customer experience. The information will only be shared with third parties in aggregate form; no individual information will be given to third parties unless we have your prior permission or you have been notified.

Does **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** use third parties?  
  
**THE PICTURE PEOPLE** uses the services of our marketing partners to provide advertising, promotions and other marketing messages. To do this, The Picture People uses web-based software and analytical tools to analyze ad campaigns and to learn more about our general audience so we may provide only the most relevant offers and promotions.

How secure is my **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** account information?  
  
We are committed to the highest standards in credit card security to protect the information you provide when you make a purchase at **THE PICTURE PEOPLE.** Our servers use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), an advanced encryption technology to protect the storage and transfer of your data from unauthorized parties. **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** also uses a digital secure server ID to provide you with the best possible protection on the Internet.  
To protect your account information, **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** requires you to enter a valid username and password before making a purchase using your existing account information.   
Additionally, **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your information. Only select employees and agents of **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** have access to this information. This information is accessed for the sole purpose of completing your order.

Are my per sonal messages private when I purchase gifts from **THE PICTURE PEOPLE**?

When you add a personal message to your order, **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** endeavors to protect the privacy of your message. For the purposes of order fulfillment, however, your message may be viewed by an order processing representative. We require our partners and employees to adhere to the strictest standards of confidentiality to protect your privacy.

Does **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** ensure the security and privacy practices of other sites to which it links?  
  
While we carefully select the web sites to which we link, we are not responsible for the privacy practice or the content of these web sites. We provide these links for convenience only. You need to make your own decisions regarding your interactions or communications with any other web site. When you provide personal information at one of those sites, you are subject to the privacy policy of the operator of that site, not to the **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** privacy policy. We encourage you to read that policy before submitting any personal information. 

How will I know when **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** changes its privacy policy?  
  
Our privacy policy is regularly reviewed to make sure we continue to serve the privacy interests of our customers. If our information practices change materially, we will post the policy changes on the privacy page of this web site to notify you of these changes. You should check our web site periodically for more information on how we use the data we collect.

Children's Online Privacy Policy  
  
The PicturePeople.com web site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that a child has provided PicturePeople.com with personally identifiable information, we ask that a parent or guardian contact PicturePeople.com in writing and we will remove any identified personal information immediately.

Contact Us   
  
If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the above addresses or phone number.   
If you are contacted by us and do not wish to receive further information please let us know by writing to us at:   

The Picture People   
1800 10th Street, Suite 300   
Plano, TX  75074   
Or you can reach us by telephone at 1-877-YOU-GRIN. 

We will act promptly to honor your request and remove your name from our database. However, even if we remove your name for use in our marketing programs, you may still receive offers and other promotional materials from outside vendors or service providers if they obtained your name before it was removed or from a source other than The Picture People. 

Terms and Conditions of Use 

Your use of the PicturePeople.com web site constitutes your agreement to follow these rules and be bound by them. If you do not agree with any of these Terms and Conditions, you are not permitted to use the PicturePeople.com web site. We reserve the right to update or modify these Terms and Conditions at any time without prior notice.

Copyright Notice 

> Portraits:
> 
> Except as specifically authorized through the sale of a product or service, or on a written release signed by us, images and information from this site may not be reproduced in any way. All images created by photography or any other means by The Picture People are the property of The Picture People, our licensing partners, or are used with permission.
> 
> Content:
> 
> All of the content on the PicturePeople.com web site, including, for example, all of the page headers, images, illustrations, graphics, audio clips, video clips, and text (collectively "content"), are subject to trademark, service mark, trade dress, copyright and/or other intellectual property rights or licenses (collectively "rights") held by The Picture People, one of our affiliated companies or by third parties who have licensed their materials to us or to one of our subsidiaries. The entire content of the PicturePeople.com web site is copyrighted as a collective work under U.S . copyright laws. 
> 
> In addition to The Picture People's Rights in individual elements of the contents, The Picture People owns a copyright in the selection, coordination, arrangement and enhancement of the content. You may not modify, publish, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale of, reproduce, create derivative works from, distribute, perform, display, incorporate into another web site, or in any other way exploit any of the content, in whole or in part. 
> 
> Except as otherwise provided in a written agreement from The Picture People, the content of the PicturePeople.com web site, and the site as a whole, are intended solely for personal, non-commercial use by the users of our site. You may download, print and studio selected portions of the Content, provided you (1) only use these copies of the content for your own personal, non-commercial use, (2) do not copy or post the content on any network computer or broadcast the content in any medium, and (3) do not modify or alter the content in any way, or delete or change any copyright or trademark notice. 
> 
> No right, title or interest in any downloaded materials is transferred to you as a result of any such downloading. The Picture People reserve complete title and full intellectual property rights in any content you download from this web site. 
> 
> Except as noted above, you may not copy, download, reproduce, modify, publish, distribute, transmit, transfer or create derivative works from the content without first obtaining written permission from The Picture People.  
> 

Disclaimers

The PicturePeople.com web site is operated on an "as is," "as available" basis, without representations or warranties of any kind, either expressed or implied. To the fullest extent permissible pursuant to applicable law, The Picture People, and our affiliated companies disclaim any and all representations and warranties with respect to this site and its contents, whether express, implied, or statutory, including, but not limited to, warranties of title, merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. 

**The Picture People** does not warrant that the functions contained in the materials will be uninterrupted or error-free, that defects will be corrected, or that this site or the server that makes it available are free of viruses or other harmful components. The Picture People does not warrant or make any representation regarding the use or the results of the use of the materials in this site in terms of their correctness, accuracy, reliability, or otherwise. Colors and availability of products at the studios may vary. You assume the entire cost of all necessary servicing, repair or correction. Applicable law may not allow the exclusion of implied warranties so the above exclusion may not apply to you. 

The Picture People makes no representation that content provided on the PicturePeople.com web site is applicable or appropriate for use in locations outside of the United States.

Your California Privacy Rights 

If you reside in California and have provided your personal information to us, you may request certain information once per calendar year about our disclosures of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Within 30 days of receiving your request, we will provide you with a list of the categories of personal information disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of these third parties. To make such a request, please send an email to [donotshare@picturepeople.com](mailto:donotshare@picturepeople.com) or write us: The Picture People, 1800 10th Street, Suite 300 Plano, TX  75074\. Please note that you must direct your request to the email address or business address specified in this paragraph. 

Effective Date

This Privacy Policy, as amended, is effective as of March 14, 2006.

How do I contact **THE PICTURE PEOPLE** if I still have questions?

You may contact us by using the Contact Us link, under Customer Care at picturepeople.com. We try to reply promptly to every message we receive. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. We may also file your comments and share them with our Customer Service team to improve our service in the future. Your personal information will only be shared with third parties in the event that we need to follow up with specific order-related questions or comments; the third parties will not use your information for promotional or any other purposes.  
If you still have questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, please write us at:
